Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about weddings.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊的是婚礼。
That's right.
没错。
We are having a wedding but we're actually planning all the things out for the wedding.
我们要办一场婚礼，但实际上我们正在为婚礼筹划所有事情。
That's right.
没错。
So there are lots of things to think about when you're planning a wedding and I don't
所以筹划婚礼时有很多事情要考虑，我觉得
think that the woman in today's dialogue has forgotten anything.
今天对话里的那位女士应该没落下什么。
Let's take a listen to the dialogue first and we'll be back in a moment.
我们先来听一下对话，一会儿再回来。
Trina, will you marry me?
Trina，你愿意嫁给我吗？
Yes, yes, yes!
愿意，愿意，愿意！
Jared, of course I'll marry you.
Jared，我当然愿意嫁给你。
Oh babe, I can't wait to spend the rest of my life with you.
哦宝贝，我等不及要和你共度余生。
I can't wait for all the adventures we're going to have, for all the fights and the
我等不及要经历我们所有的冒险，所有的争吵和
laughter.
欢笑。
I can't wait to grow old and wrinkly with you.
我等不及要和你一起变老、长皱纹。
Oh Jared, I can't wait for our wedding.
哦Jared，我等不及要办我们的婚礼了。
I hope you don't mind but I've already chosen a date, six months from now in the summer.
希望你别介意，但我已经选好了日子，六个月后的夏天。
Melissa saw you buying the ring last month so I had plenty of time to start planning.
Melissa上个月看到你买戒指了，所以我有很多时间开始筹划。
She what?
她什么？
Oh, don't worry sweetie.
哦，别担心亲爱的。
I didn't know when you were going to propose.
我不知道你什么时候会求婚。
It was still a nice surprise.
这仍然是个惊喜。
As I was saying, I've got it all planned out.
就像我说的，我已经全部计划好了。
There's almost nothing left to do.
几乎没什么要做的了。
I wrote up our guest list and we will have roughly 400 guests attending.
我写了我们的宾客名单，大概会有400位客人参加。
400?
400位？
No need to sweat it.
别紧张。
My parents agreed to pay for most of the wedding, which is going to be a low budget anyway.
我父母同意支付婚礼的大部分费用，反正预算也不高。
So roughly 400 people, which means that the hall at Northwood Heights will be our reception
所以大概400人，这意味着Northwood Heights的大厅将是我们婚宴的
venue.
场地。
I thought it would be nice if we had the wedding at your parents' church, and my uncle of
我觉得如果我们在你父母的教堂办婚礼会很好，当然我叔叔
course would be officiating.
会主持仪式。
We'll meet with him soon for some pre-wedding counselling.
我们很快会和他见面做婚前辅导。
The music for the wedding ceremony was a no-brainer.
婚礼仪式的音乐是明摆着的事。
My stepsister and her string quartet will take care of that.
我继姐和她的弦乐四重奏会负责。
My cousin will be the official photographer.
我表弟会是官方摄影师。
I thought it would also be nice if his daughter could sing a solo.
我觉得他女儿能唱个独唱也不错。
Did you know that she's going to be a professional opera singer?
你知道她要成为专业歌剧演员了吗？
And then of course the ladies at the church would love to be our caterers for the banquet
然后当然教堂的女士们很乐意做我们宴会的餐饮，
and will get the youth group to serve us.
还会让青年团来服务我们。
I was thinking that your friend's band could be our entertainment for the night, though
我在想你朋友的乐队可以当晚上的娱乐节目，不过
they might have to tone it down a bit.
他们可能得收敛一点。
Or we could hire a DJ.
或者我们可以雇个DJ。
Your sister's husband could get us a discount with that company that does the decor at weddings.
你姐姐的丈夫可以帮我们在那家做婚礼装饰的公司拿到折扣。
What's their name again?
他们叫什么名字来着？
I was thinking that we could have an island paradise themed wedding and our theme colour
我在想我们可以办个海岛天堂主题的婚礼，我们的主题色
would be a soothing blue-like aquamarine.
会是舒缓的蓝色，比如海蓝宝石色。
And there would be a huge seashell on the wall behind the podium where we'll make our
讲台后面的墙上会有一个巨大的贝壳，我们会在那里
toasts.
敬酒。
What do you think of small packages of drink mixes for our wedding favours?
你觉得用小包装的饮料粉做婚礼回礼怎么样？
Who else am I missing?
我还漏了谁？
Oh, your uncle could be our florist and his wife could make our wedding cake.
哦，你叔叔可以当我们的花艺师，他妻子可以做我们的婚礼蛋糕。
Oh wow.
哦哇。
See, it's going to be wonderful.
看，一切都会很棒的。
Oh, this wedding is going to be everything I ever dreamed of.
哦，这场婚礼会是我梦想的一切。
If I survive the next six months.
如果我能熬过接下来的六个月。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So she talked a lot.
她说了很多。
So there are a lot of words and phrases here that we're going to take a look at.
这里有很多单词和短语我们要看一下。
So let's start with a couple of them on Language Takeaway.
我们先从“语言要点”里的几个开始。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright so on Language Takeaway, why don't we start off with the first word and the basic
好的，在“语言要点”里，我们不如从第一个词和基本的
one.
那个开始。
When you plan a wedding, the guy needs to propose.
筹划婚礼时，男方需要求婚。
Or the woman.
或者女方。
Let's be 21st century here.
我们得跟上21世纪。
Normally it's the man but to propose in this instance means to propose marriage.
通常是男方，但在这里“propose”指的是求婚。
So basically this is the part where someone gets down on his knee and he says, you know,
所以基本上就是有人单膝跪地，然后说，你知道，
sweetie pie, I want to be with you forever.
“甜心，我想永远和你在一起。”
Will you marry me?
“你愿意嫁给我吗？”
Right.
对。
To propose.
求婚。
So to propose is to ask someone to marry you.
所以“propose”就是请求某人嫁给你。
That's right.
没错。
But it can also mean something else, right?
但它也可以有其他意思，对吧？
To suggest.
建议。
That's right.
没错。
So I could propose an idea.
所以我可以提出一个想法。
Or I could propose a plan.
或者我可以提出一个计划。
But in this case, to propose has another meaning and it's basically to ask someone to marry
但在这里，"propose" 有另一个意思，基本上就是向某人求婚。
you.
你。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So now we've proposed to someone.
所以现在我们向某人求婚了。
So we need to start planning our wedding and I think one of the first steps is you need
所以我们需要开始计划婚礼，我认为第一步是你要
to know how many people are going to be there and who you're going to invite.
知道会有多少人参加，以及你要邀请谁。
That's right.
没错。
So when you're planning a wedding, you have to think about the people that are going to
所以当你计划婚礼时，你必须考虑那些会
attend the wedding so you prepare a guest list.
参加婚礼的人，所以你要准备一份宾客名单。
Okay.
好的。
So a guest list.
所以是宾客名单。
Now it's pretty simple, right?
这很简单，对吧？
You have a list where you put everyone's name there and you know how many people are coming.
你有一份名单，把每个人的名字写上去，就知道有多少人会来。
Exactly.
正是如此。
Okay.
好的。
A guest list.
宾客名单。
Now you have your guest list and now you need to pick a place where your wedding will be.
现在你有了宾客名单，然后你需要选一个举行婚礼的地方。
That's right.
没错。
So we often talk about two parts to a wedding.
所以我们经常谈论婚礼的两个部分。
The first part is the ceremony, the wedding ceremony.
第一部分是仪式，婚礼仪式。
Maybe if you're religious, that happens in a church.
如果你有宗教信仰，那可能在教堂举行。
Okay.
好的。
But there's a party afterwards and that's what we're talking about here.
但之后会有一个派对，我们这里讨论的就是这个。
We're talking about a reception.
我们说的是婚宴。
Okay.
好的。
A reception is basically the party part of the wedding where you drink and eat and listen
婚宴基本上是婚礼的派对部分，在那里你喝酒、吃饭、听
to music and dance.
音乐和跳舞。
So obviously for that, you need a space, a place to have the party and we call it the
所以显然，你需要一个空间，一个举办派对的地方，我们称之为
reception venue.
婚宴场地。
Okay.
好的。
A venue.
场地。
So as you said, the reception is the party and the venue is the place where you have
所以正如你所说，婚宴是派对，场地是你举办
it.
它的地方。
Now a venue is not a specific word, right?
现在"venue"这个词不是特指某个地方，对吧？
You can use venue for many different places.
你可以用"venue"指代很多不同的地方。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, someone's having a concert, I can ask him, hey, what's the venue?
比如，有人要开音乐会，我可以问他，嘿，场地在哪里？
Okay.
好的。
That means what is the theater or where's this place you're going to have the concert?
意思就是剧院在哪里，或者你打算在哪里举办音乐会？
Okay.
好的。
So for example, a stadium can be a venue or a restaurant can be a venue.
比如，体育场可以是一个场地，餐厅也可以是一个场地。
Exactly.
正是如此。
So a venue is a place where an event can be held.
所以"venue"就是可以举办活动的地方。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So now we have our reception venue.
现在我们有了婚宴场地。
We have our guest list and the girl was talking about her uncle officiating.
我们有了宾客名单，那个女孩提到她叔叔主持婚礼。
What does she mean by to officiate?
她说的"to officiate"是什么意思？
Okay.
好的。
So like you said, the verb here is to officiate.
所以就像你说的，这里的动词是"to officiate"。
Her uncle will be officiating.
她叔叔将主持婚礼。
That means he will be the person who marries them.
意思就是他将是主持他们结婚的人。
So maybe you've seen movies before where there's a priest who says, you know, do you take this
你可能在电影里见过，有个牧师说，你知道，你愿意娶这位
woman to be your lawfully wedded wife until death do you part?
女士为合法妻子，直到死亡将你们分开吗？
That person who says that, the person who asks the questions, he or she officiates.
说那些话的人，问问题的那个人，他或她主持婚礼。
Okay.
好的。
Officiate.
主持。
So that's basically the action of marrying someone or leading the ceremony.
所以这基本上就是主持结婚或引导仪式的行为。
That's right.
没错。
And in America, this isn't just anybody.
在美国，这不是随便什么人都能做的。
Someone has to have a license or has to be a priest and has to have the authority to
必须有人有执照，或者是牧师，并且有权力
officiate.
主持。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So that's a very interesting word there too, officiate.
所以"officiate"这个词也很有趣。
Now moving on, when we talk about the food for the reception venue, well, we need somebody
现在继续，当我们谈论婚宴场地的食物时，我们需要有人
to cook it and prepare it and that's when we hire caterers.
来烹饪和准备，这时我们就雇佣餐饮服务商。
That's right.
没错。
So a caterer is kind of like a cook, but a caterer basically arranges a meal for many
所以"caterer"有点像厨师，但餐饮服务商基本上是为很多人
people.
安排餐食。
And usually the person will bring the food to you.
而且通常他们会把食物送到你那里。
So for example, if we're going to have a party, Marco, and we're going to throw it at a venue
比如，如果我们要办派对，Marco，我们要在10英里外的场地
10 miles away, the caterer will bring the food to us.
举办，餐饮服务商会把食物送到我们这里。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a caterer.
所以那就是餐饮服务商。
You get someone to cater your wedding.
你找人来承办你的婚礼餐饮。
That's right.
没错。
Or cater a party.
或者承办派对餐饮。
So I've had parties before that I've called caterers to make the food for.
我以前办过派对，叫过餐饮服务商来准备食物。
So basically they work with me and I tell them the kind of food I would like and they
所以基本上他们和我一起工作，我告诉他们我想要的食物，然后他们
prepare it.
准备。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And now for our last part for the wedding planning, you have the food, you have the
现在到了婚礼策划的最后一部分，你有食物，你有
venue, you have everything, but you also need to decorate a little bit and this is when
场地，你什么都有了，但还需要稍微装饰一下，这时候
you call a florist.
你要找花艺师。
Florist.
花艺师。
So this sounds a lot like flower, right?
这听起来很像“花”，对吧？
Florist flower.
花艺师和花。
And that's basically what this person does.
这基本上就是这个人做的事情。
A florist is a person who prepares flowers or who cuts flowers and uses them to decorate.
花艺师是准备鲜花或修剪鲜花并用它们来装饰的人。
Okay.
好的。
So you go to the florist to buy flowers, roses and different types of things.
所以你去花艺师那里买花、玫瑰和各种不同的东西。
Okay.
好的。
A florist.
花艺师。
Very good.
很好。
So we have six key words there that are related to planning a wedding.
所以我们有六个与策划婚礼相关的关键词。
Why don't we move on now to a couple of phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在我们继续看“流利度构建器”中的几个短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
All right.
好的。
So this first phrase is a really good one.
第一个短语非常好。
It's a little bit gross.
有点恶心。
We're talking about sweat.
我们在说“出汗”。
The woman in this dialogue says, hey, no need to sweat it.
对话中的女人说：“嘿，不用紧张。”
So what does this mean?
这是什么意思？
All right.
好的。
So if you say to sweat means when you're running, you're doing exercise, it's hot, water starts
如果你说“出汗”，意思是当你跑步、做运动、天气热时，水开始
to come out of your skin.
从皮肤里出来。
Yummy.
真美味。
Right.
对吧。
But if the person says, hey, don't sweat it or no need to sweat it, it's a colloquial
但如果有人说：“嘿，别紧张”或“不用紧张”，这是一种口语化的
way of saying, don't worry.
说法，意思是“别担心”。
Okay.
好的。
So we're not actually talking about sweat here.
所以我们这里实际上不是在说出汗。
So maybe Marco, you and I are working on a project together and I say, listen, Marco,
所以也许马可，你和我一起做一个项目，我说：“听着，马可，
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
I have a family emergency.
我有家庭紧急情况。
I can't finish the project with you.
我不能和你一起完成这个项目了。
Would you be able to help me out?
你能帮我一下吗？
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。”
Sure, sure.
“当然，当然。
Don't sweat it.
别紧张。
It's not a problem.
没问题。”
Okay.
好的。
So don't worry.
所以别担心。
Don't worry.
别担心。
Right.
对吧。
So if you tell someone to not sweat it, don't sweat it, or no need to sweat it, you're basically
所以如果你告诉某人“别紧张”、“别紧张”或“不用紧张”，你基本上
telling them it's okay.
是在告诉他们没关系。
It's not a problem.
没问题。
Everything's going to be fine.
一切都会好的。
Great.
太好了。
So the next phrase here is also kind of relaxed.
下一个短语也比较随意。
It's kind of laid back.
比较放松。
So the woman is still describing some of the things she's prepared for the wedding and
女人还在描述她为婚礼准备的一些东西，
she says, hey, listen, don't worry.
她说：“嘿，听着，别担心。
The music was a no brainer.
音乐是件简单的事。”
Okay.
好的。
No brainer.
简单的事。
Okay.
好的。
This is really easy.
这真的很简单。
Well, your brain is inside your head, right?
嗯，你的大脑在头里面，对吧？
So if you say no brainer, it's basically saying you don't have to think about it too much
所以如果你说“简单的事”，基本上就是说你不用想太多，
or it's very easy, very simple.
或者很容易、很简单。
Okay.
好的。
So I was deciding on where to go on vacation and the options were Thailand or Antarctica.
所以我在决定去哪里度假，选项是泰国或南极洲。
That's a no brainer.
那是个简单的事。
Thailand.
泰国。
Obviously, I want to go where it's sunny and warm.
显然，我想去阳光明媚、温暖的地方。
So a no brainer means I didn't even have to think about it.
所以“简单的事”意思是我想都不用想。
It was that easy.
就这么容易。
Right.
对吧。
The decision making was a no brainer.
做决定是件简单的事。
All right.
好的。
So for our next phrase, the girl was also talking about the music and she was talking
下一个短语，女孩也在谈论音乐，她在谈论
about a band, maybe like a rock band and she said, well, maybe they could play, but they
一个乐队，也许是摇滚乐队，她说：“嗯，他们也许可以演奏，但他们
would need to tone it down.
需要低调一点。”
Okay.
好的。
So this is a favorite phrase of parents, I think, all over the English speaking world.
这大概是父母们最喜欢的短语，我想，在整个英语世界里。
Tone it down.
收敛一点。
In this case, we're talking about music.
在这个例子里，我们说的是音乐。
So maybe like you said, the friend's band is a rock and roll band and it's really loud
所以就像你说的，朋友的乐队是个摇滚乐队，声音很大
and angry and in your face, but for a wedding, that's not appropriate.
又愤怒又咄咄逼人，但婚礼上这样不合适。
So to tone it down means to make it more appropriate for the occasion.
所以“收敛一点”意思是让它更适合场合。
So maybe less loud or no offensive language or no swear words.
比如声音小一点，或者没有冒犯性语言，没有脏话。
Right.
对。
That's basically what tone it down means, right?
这基本上就是“收敛一点”的意思，对吧？
If someone says you need to tone it down, it's a little bit more direct.
如果有人对你说需要收敛一点，那比较直接。
Like you said, if your parents tell you this, it's maybe because you're being a little bit
就像你说的，如果你父母这么对你说，可能是因为你有点
too loud or you're yelling or you're being irrespectful.
太吵了，或者你在喊叫，或者你不尊重人。
So that's why your parents would tell you, hey, you need to tone it down a bit.
所以这就是为什么你父母会对你说，嘿，你需要收敛一点。
That's right.
没错。
Or sometimes we have this in the office where someone doesn't understand how to communicate
或者有时候在办公室里，有人不知道怎么用
in a positive way.
积极的方式沟通。
And so they say, oh, that paper you did was really bad.
然后他们说，哦，你写的那份报告真差劲。
It was stupid.
真蠢。
I don't ever want to see it again.
我再也不想看到了。
Say, well, maybe you need to tone it down a little bit.
然后你说，嗯，也许你需要收敛一点。
Think about the words you're using and make them a little bit less harsh.
想想你用的词，让它们不那么尖锐。
So kind of to relax, to reduce your level of being aggressive, being loud, that's to
所以就是放松一点，降低你的攻击性和吵闹程度，这就是
tone it down.
收敛一点。
Exactly.
完全正确。
Okay.
好的。
A lot of great phrases there.
这里有很多好短语。
Why don't we now go back, listen to our great dialogue one last time and we'll be back to
我们现在不如回去，最后再听一遍我们的精彩对话，然后我们会回来
talk a little bit more.
再聊一会儿。
Trina, will you marry me?
特瑞娜，你愿意嫁给我吗？
Yes, yes, yes.
愿意，愿意，愿意。
Jared, of course I'll marry you.
杰瑞德，我当然愿意嫁给你。
Oh babe, I can't wait to spend the rest of my life with you.
哦宝贝，我等不及要和你共度余生了。
I can't wait for all the adventures we're going to have, for all the fights and the
我等不及要经历我们所有的冒险，所有的争吵和
laughter.
欢笑。
I can't wait to grow old and wrinkly with you.
我等不及要和你一起变老，长出皱纹。
Oh Jared, I can't wait for our wedding.
哦杰瑞德，我等不及我们的婚礼了。
I hope you don't mind, but I've already chosen a date six months from now in the summer.
希望你别介意，但我已经选好了日期，六个月后的夏天。
Melissa saw you buying the ring last month, so I had plenty of time to start planning.
梅丽莎上个月看到你买戒指了，所以我有足够的时间开始计划。
She what?
她什么？
Oh don't worry sweetie, I didn't know when you were going to propose.
哦别担心亲爱的，我不知道你什么时候会求婚。
It was still a nice surprise.
这仍然是个惊喜。
As I was saying, I've got it all planned out.
就像我说的，我都计划好了。
There's almost nothing left to do.
几乎没什么要做的了。
I wrote up our guest list and we will have roughly 400 guests attending.
我写了我们的宾客名单，大概会有400位客人参加。
400?
400位？
No need to sweat it.
别担心。
My parents agreed to pay for most of the wedding, which is going to be a low budget anyway.
我父母同意支付婚礼的大部分费用，而且这本来就是个低预算的婚礼。
So roughly 400 people, which means that the hall at Northwood Heights will be our reception
所以大概400人，这意味着诺斯伍德高地的宴会厅将是我们的婚宴
venue.
场地。
I thought it would be nice if we had the wedding at your parents' church, and my uncle of course
我觉得如果我们在你父母的教堂举行婚礼会很好，当然我叔叔
would be officiating.
会主持仪式。
We'll meet with him soon for some pre-wedding counselling.
我们很快会和他见面做婚前辅导。
The music for the wedding ceremony was a no-brainer.
婚礼仪式的音乐是明摆着的。
My stepsister and her string quartet will take care of that.
我继姐和她的弦乐四重奏会负责。
My cousin will be the official photographer.
我表弟会是官方摄影师。
I thought it would also be nice if his daughter could sing a solo.
我觉得他女儿能独唱一首歌也不错。
Did you know that she's going to be a professional opera singer?
你知道她将来会成为专业歌剧歌手吗？
And then of course the ladies at the church would love to be our caterers for the banquet
然后当然，教堂的女士们会很乐意做我们宴会的餐饮服务，
and will get the youth group to serve us.
还会让青年团来服务我们。
I was thinking that your friend's band could be our entertainment for the night, though
我在想你朋友的乐队可以为我们晚上的娱乐表演，不过
they might have to turn it down a bit.
他们可能需要把音量调小一点。
Or we could hire a DJ.
或者我们可以雇个DJ。
Your sister's husband could get us a discount with that company that does the decor at weddings.
你姐姐的丈夫可以帮我们在那家做婚礼装饰的公司拿到折扣。
What's their name again?
那家公司叫什么来着？
I was thinking that we could have an island paradise themed wedding, and our theme colour
我在想我们可以办一个海岛天堂主题的婚礼，我们的主题色
would be a soothing blue-like aquamarine.
会是舒缓的蓝色，比如海蓝宝石色。
And there will be a huge seashell on the wall behind the podium where we'll make our toasts.
在讲台后面的墙上会有一个巨大的贝壳，我们会在那里敬酒。
What do you think of small packages of drink mixes for our wedding favours?
你觉得用小包装的饮料粉做婚礼回礼怎么样？
Who else am I missing?
我还漏了谁？
Oh, your uncle could be our florist, and his wife could make our wedding cake.
哦，你叔叔可以当我们的花商，他妻子可以做我们的婚礼蛋糕。
Oh wow.
哦哇。
See, it's going to be wonderful.
看，这将会很精彩。
Oh, this wedding is going to be everything I ever dreamed of.
哦，这场婚礼将会是我梦想中的一切。
If I survive the next six months.
如果我能熬过接下来的六个月。
Alright so about weddings and planning out a wedding, do you think 400 guests is a small
好了，关于婚礼和策划婚礼，你觉得400位客人算小
wedding?
婚礼吗？
No.
不。
No, this woman is out of control.
不，这个女人失控了。
In fact, in English, we have a word for a bride, or like a woman who's getting married,
事实上，在英语里，我们有一个词来形容新娘，或者一个要结婚的女人，
that describes someone who's completely nuts about the wedding.
形容那种对婚礼完全着迷的人。
We call her a bridezilla.
我们叫她“新娘怪兽”。
Bridezilla.
新娘怪兽。
Like Godzilla.
就像哥斯拉一样。
Exactly, the movie Godzilla.
没错，就是电影《哥斯拉》。
He's a monster.
他是个怪物。
And he's out of control.
而且他失控了。
He's out of control.
他失控了。
And a bride who's so obsessed with her wedding that nothing else is important, she is a bridezilla.
一个对自己的婚礼痴迷到其他一切都不重要的新娘，就是新娘怪兽。
Now it's a very big thing for a woman, right, for her wedding to be nice and perfect and
对女人来说，婚礼要办得漂亮完美，这是件大事，对吧？
everything.
一切。
Do you think guys are more relaxed in this sense?
你觉得男人在这方面更放松吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think it depends on the guy, as always.
我觉得这因人而异，和往常一样。
There are some people who want to be very involved, and some people who don't care.
有些人想积极参与，有些人则不在乎。
But in general, I think men are less worried about the details.
但总的来说，我认为男人不太担心细节。
Just as long as there's a wedding, it's fine.
只要有婚礼就行，没问题。
Exactly.
没错。
Although a lot of men, when the wedding actually happens, start to get very nervous.
不过很多男人在婚礼真正举行时，会开始变得非常紧张。
But kind of like having doubts, maybe cold feet.
但有点像产生怀疑，也许是临阵退缩。
Yes, cold feet.
是的，临阵退缩。
Like should I get married?
比如“我该结婚吗？”
Should I not get married?
“我不该结婚吗？”
I think it's very interesting because you see this in movies a lot.
我觉得这很有趣，因为你在电影里经常看到这种情况。
And I've always wondered how often or how common is it for a guy or a girl to say no
我一直想知道，一个男人或女人在婚礼已经开始时说“不”或离开，这种情况有多常见？
or to leave a wedding when it has already started.
或者离开已经开始的婚礼。
Because you know, you have invited all these people, all these friends and family, maybe
因为你邀请了所有人，所有朋友和家人，也许
people came from different countries, and food is paid for, venue.
有人从不同国家赶来，食物和场地都付了钱。
You spend so much money on a wedding and for you to say no.
你在婚礼上花了这么多钱，然后你说“不”。
I don't know how common it is.
我不知道这有多常见。
It's very common in movies, but I really don't know anyone who's experienced this.
这在电影里很常见，但我真的不认识经历过这种事的人。
I don't either, actually, now that you bring it up.
说实话，你一提起来，我也不认识。
So maybe we could talk about this.
所以也许我们可以聊聊这个。
Is this common in your country?
这在你们国家常见吗？
First of all, do people spend a lot of money on weddings?
首先，人们在婚礼上花很多钱吗？
And second of all, have you ever heard of someone actually leaving the wedding before
其次，你听说过有人在婚礼结束前离开吗？
they finished?
在结束前？
Yes, during the ceremony.
是的，在仪式期间。
Not before, during.
不是之前，是期间。
During the ceremony.
在仪式期间。
So our website is EnglishPod.com.
所以我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
And we hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
Until next time.
下次见。
Bye.
再见。